BENJAMIN SHULER

P: (530) 564-9419 E: benjaminshuler@gmail.com **L:** linkedin.com/in/benshuler **G:** github.com/bensdata

Summary

I decided to become a data analyst because my experience in SAAS sales taught me the value of data and software tools. Working with c-suite decision makers, it was important for me to completely understand their challenges and how to help them. Most often, they needed someone to go into the weeds and do the dirty work. They needed someone to find the answers that would help them make key decisions or manage a set of risks. Now I want to be the guy that finds the solution, not just the guy talking about the solution. As a data analyst, it is my goal to take the hairy problems and deliver actionable results, to turn data into insight.

Experience

Nashville Software School

Junior Data Analyst | Nashville, TN | March 2020 – Present

Summary: A 3-month full time bootcamp covering the essential data analyst tool set, including: Python, SQL, Tableau, Power BI, and Excel. Through project-based hands-on learning, learned data organization, exploratory data analysis, visualization, and storytelling.

- SQL: Write queries to filter, aggregate, sort, group, and join data from relational databases. Use queries to perform simple, intermediate, and complex calculations over a database and report the answers to any particular question
- Tableau and Power BI: Use data to create visualizations and interactive dashboards that provide key insights and solutions. Use storytelling methods to make the ultimate recommendation more impactful to the audience and key stakeholders.
- Python: Use Pandas, Matplotlib, and Seaborn libraries to gather, analyze, and visualize data.
- Microsoft Excel: Analyze large data sets using built-in functions, logical conditions, lookup formulas, pivot tables, and Excel add-ins. Visualize and present data in an easy-to-understand way using charts, sparklines, and conditional formatting.

Capstone Project

Using medicare prescriber and physician compare data, I explored the prescribing patterns of physicians and whether or not there exists a correlation with specific institutions (med-schools, residencies, hospital affiliations). The tools I used were python, SQL, and tableau.

Tableau Project

In a hypothetical scenario presenting to Nashville police leadership, used Tableau to explore Nashville traffic accident data from 2019 to identify which zip codes had the highest number of accidents, what time of day the most accidents occurred, and which officers had the highest reporting rates and postulate why that might be.

SQL Project

As team lead, used SQL to explore questions within the Lahman baseball database. Led the team using Kanban boards to divide and delegate the workload. Using pull requests, merged separate SQL queries to one master branch.

NCONTRACTS

Business Development Officer | Brentwood, TN | 2019 - 2020

- Ncontracts is a SAAS company that provides software and services that help financial institutions manage regulatory and operational risk.
- As business development officer, I worked with banking and credit union C-suite individuals in order to help assess their risk management needs and provide the appropriate solution.
- Increased company recurring revenue by \$100K

RISKALYZE

Advisor Solutions Representative | Auburn, CA | 2018 - 2019

- SaaS account executive to independent financial advisor prospects nationwide.
- Facilitate deals via remote and in-person demos, evangelizing the value of Riskalyze software suite.
- Reliably exceed monthly sales goals and achieved company new hire sales record.

SOLAR/REROOF SALES EXECUTIVE

Solar Roof Dynamics Llc | Davis, CA | 2017 - 2018

- Established long-term relationships with dealers to achieve sales and install goals.
- Facilitated two key dealer partnerships and spearheaded the inside sales model, resulting in 70% increase in revenue that was critical to the start-up's growth.
- Spearheaded market penetration for new solar roofing product (an alternative to Tesla roof).
- Ran field marketing efforts at local green energy and solar industry events.

PetersenDean | Northern California, CA | 2016 - 2017

- Primary point of contact for all projects from acquisition to completion.
- Strong metrics in closing, referral, and profit margin with below 5% cancellation rate.
- Surpassed annual quota by 16% and exceeded Q4 goal by 50%, totaling \$1.5 million in sales.

SunEdison | Sacramento, CA | 2015 - 2016

- Self-generated, signed, and managed sales with customers throughout Northern California.
- Maintained 85% close rate and < 10% cancellation rate.

DESIGNS FOR HEALTH

Account Manager / Practice Consultant | Austin, TX | 2009 - 2012

- Direct-to-clinician consultative sales of nutritional protocols targeting diet- and lifestyle-related illness.
- Managed key accounts in Central Texas, including mental health and primary care clinicians, generating > 10% revenue growth per quarter.

BEHOLD DESIGN

Business Development | San Francisco, CA | 2012 - 2015

- Spearheaded expansion and development initiatives in Midwest region and Northern California.
- Generated business for interactive web design campaigns and digital application design projects.

US FOOD AND DRUG ADMINISTRATION

Customer Safety Officer | Cincinnati, OH | 2010 - 2011

- Investigated complaints of injury, illness, or death caused by an FDA-regulated product.
- Performed inspections, documented all violations, generated reports, and worked with compliance officers on cases.

Education

NASHVILLE SOFTWARE SCHOOL

Junior Data Analyst | Nashville, TN | 2020

THE OHIO STATE UNIVERSITY

Bachelor of Science, Human Ecology, Minor in Business | Columbus, OH | 2009